Adebayo Akingbade

I am your favourite product engineer with years of experience building software applications from the ground up-gathering information, planning, designing, developing, testing, delivering, and maintaining. I'm extremely passionate towards software architectures and designs combined with sensitivity to serve the needs of an organisation.

Royal Palm Will Estate, Badore, Ajah, Lagos State, Nigeria, NG

(+234) 9018380825

adejeremih@gmail.com https://github.com/AdebayoAkingbade

EXPERIENCE

CONCLASE - Frontend Engineer

August 2022 - September 2023

Conclase is a tech company that empowers companies to achieve more through; tech recruiting, web and software development, project outsourcing and capacity building. Here in Conclase I worked with a team to build e-commerce apps e.g. tracnine.

SILICON JUNGLE LABS, Austin Texas — Frontend Engineer (Contract)

January 2022 - June 2022

A member of a team that developed a social money pooling app.

- Built project with GraphQL, React and Typescript.
- Experience in writing unit and integration test

DECAGON, Lagos — Software Engineer

August 2020 - July 2022

A member of a team that developed a social media app.

- Built project with NodeJS, RestAPI, React and Typescript.
- Handles Database Management System with MongoDB
- Experience in writing unit and integration test

EDUCATION

Kebbi State University of Science and Technology, Aliero — B.Sc

October 2012 - September 2016

Second Class Honor - Bachelor of Science degree in Statistics.

TECHNOLOGIES

ReactJS

Redux

Typescript

Vite

Microsoft Office

HTML 5

CSS

Firebase

Netlify

Vercel

Version Control with Git and

Github

Performance Optimization

Accessibility

PWA

Test-Driven development.

CERTIFICATIONS

DECAGON - Software

Engineering

GOOGLE - Foundations of

Project Management

VMEdu, Inc at SCRUMstudy-

Scrum Fundamentals

Certified(SFC)

PROJECTS

TRACNINE — Web Application

Tracnine is an ecommerce platform helping businesses to get customers for their logistics and delivery. Using React, Redux, Tailwind, RestAPI.

Tribl — Admin web Application

Tribl is a social money pooling platform building a bridge between Web3 and the culture. Using React, Redux, GraphQL.

Luno Landing Page Clone

Iterated user interface and experience to meet user satisfaction and documentation Standards gotten from market research.

Link: https://luno-page.netlify.app/

Decameal App

A food web application where users can login, explore varieties of food, available in the kitchen and order for their choice.

I contributed to designing and building the dashboard, landing page, and about us page.

Technologies used: ReactJS, Typescript, and RestAPI

Link: https://decameal.netlify.app/

TRUCK LOGISTICS

A web application where customers can order for truck deliveries and registered drivers get paired with orders based on driver location.

Technologies used: NodeJS, ReactJS, Typescript, and Bootsrap

Link: https://trucksnow.netlify.app/

Contact Keeper

A contact saver that helps life even better, you don't have to overdose your phones With loads anymore. The contact keeper can help to save your contacts and free up space on your mobile.

Link: https://contact-keep.herokuapp.com/